AMAURY MAUSBACH FILHO

Address: Av.Jorge Tibiriçá, 1840 apto.11C - 13044-125 - Campinas-SP

e-mail: amausbach filho@hotmail.com - Skype: amausbachfilho

Linkedin: https://br.linkedin.com/in/amausbach

GIT: https://github.com/amausbach

Phone Numbers - Home: +55 19 3276-2526 - Mobile: +55 19 98801-2186

Goal:

Consultant, Product Manager, Project Manager, System and Software Architect, Process Specialist and Software Development in Telecommunications, Utilities, Consulting or IT Companies.

Profile:

Professional career developed as a process consultant, solution manager, engineering manager, product manager, project manager, systems architect and programming. Recent Experience acquired in applying technical expertise focused on preparation of technical proposals, solution architecture and system development for new products and services and business modeling in IT, Telecom and Utilities market.

Skills:

SELLING: Preparation of technical proposals, business modeling and presentations.

MANAGEMENT AND LIDERSHIP: Coordination and management consulting, pre-sales and development teams. **COMMUNICATION:** Didactic in preparation and transmission of concepts and ideas to the general public.

TECHNICAL: Wide knowledge on system and software architecture, software technologies, hardware, protocols, processes and standards in the IT industry / Telecom. Posture of improvement and continuous learning of new technologies.

Work Experience:

- Experience in the Brazilian Number Portability Platform having participated in the implementation of the centralized system of Brazilian portability, in partnership with Neustar, and as solution and software architect for portability solutions to operators (SOA / BDO);
- Experience in the Wholesale Trading System for the telecom services market having participated in the specification and solution and software architect for local wholesale solution to operator (BDA);
- Experience in Process and System Architecture Consulting involving technologies such as BPMN, SOA, Cloud and reference architectures based on TMForum, ITU and APQC;
- Experience in the design and product specifications, business plan development, commercial strategy definition, and product offering development;
- Experience in the management team of architects and systems engineers responsible for the architecture of the solution and preparation of technical and commercial proposals to operational support systems (OSS) and

- systems integration;
- Experience in the search and development of technology partnerships for composition of complex architectures solution for telecom market;
- Knowledge of new development and learning platforms as Arduino, Raspberry, Beaglebone, Edison, Galileo for IoT applications;
- System Architecture Knowledge aimed at networks and services covering technologies such as OSS, BSS, VAS, IMS, SDP, OSA Parlay, NGN, VoIP, MPLS, IPTV, Mesh, Wifi, Wimax, BroadBand and Dial Access, Cable TV, RFID, NFC and NFV;
- Knowledge of processes and methodologies (eTOM, NGOSS, COBIT, ITIL, CMMI, RUP, BPMN, ISO-9000, BS-17799, ESA (PSS-05)), architecture (TAM, SOA, MDA, J2EE, Corba, TOGAF), Agil(SCRUM) and management (PMI, OPM3);
- Participating in discussion forum LAB, eTOM, TAM and SLAM TMForum, having been certified as eTOM Certified Consultant;
- Wide experience in preparation of proposals and technical development projects and systems integration, and coordination of the integration teams, development and deployment for Network Management Systems and OSS Telecommunications;
- Coordination of software development teams and participation in all stages of the software development process, from requirements gathering to after-sales support, including methodological and quality assurance subjects.

International Experience:

- Participation in the TelemanagementWorld Congress (Dallas and Nice) and standardization discussion groups eTOM, TAM and SLAM;
- Development of partnerships and proposal in conjunction with multinational companies;
- Consulting and pilot project for HP-Consulting (Argentina);
- Q3 interface specification with HP-BID (Germany);
- Several courses in the United States, France and Germany.

Education:

- Marketing Executive MBA ESPM Business School, 2003;
- Master in Computer Science (26 credits completed) Universidade Estadual de Campinas (UNICAMP), 1992;
- Bachelor's degree in Computer Science Scientific and Industrial
 Universidade Estadual de Campinas (UNICAMP), 1985;

Certification: • TMFORUM - eTOM Lev 2

Languages: Portuguese: Native

English: Professional working proficiency Spanish: Limited working proficiency

Maustech, São Paulo, 2016--Main Achievements:

- Development of a remote wireless firmware upload to Arduino platform in progress;
- JavaScript Interpreter portability to PAX(Prolin) platform.

Work History:

- Research, Analysis and Software Portability on JavaScript Interpreter(ES5.1) to POS based on PAX(Prolin) device D200.
- Research and Evaluation of IoT frameworks like Arduino, Esp286, bootloader, RTOS and related protocols and technologies as CoAP, MQTT, BLE, Zigbee, SigFox, LoRA.
- Pre-sales consulting to prepared Technical Proposal on Project Management, Systems Architecture, Software Development evolving OSS/BSS software and solutions.

Cleartech, São Paulo, 2007-2015 Main Achievements:

- Product Specification and Architecture Design of Number Portability Product for Telecom Operators which was the first product sold by Cleartech and that opened a new revenue stream;
- Partner in the Specification, Architecture Design and Proposals of Wholesale Product for Telecom Operators which was a very innovative solution (unique in the world);
- Product Specification and Architecture Design, Business Plan Development of SmartGrid Product for Energy Utilities which might allow Cleartech to enter in a new market(Utilities);
- Product Specification, Architecture Design and Management of Product Development of a SIP Redirect Server based on ENUM which allowed Cleartech to be certified by GSMA
- Process Reference Architecture Design based on eTOM which allowed NET to organize all business process and improve procurement and implementation process;
- Preparation of Technical Proposal and Business Plan for Cleartech Products and Services that was responsible for almost 100% of revenues based on product licensing.

Work History:

- eTOM Process and Software Architecture Consultant at NET having developed the process reference architecture NeTOM based on TMForum eTOM model;
- Preparation of Technical Proposals involving consultancy, processes, portability, wholesale systems, OSS / BSS (cobilling, Conciliation, Interconnect), Roaming, mPayment / NFC, MVNO / MVNE and SmartGrid;
- Business Plan Development for MVNO / MVNE and SmartGrid (InovaTelecom);
- Architect and Senior Business Analyst having developed the specification of the Law Enforcement system, portability product CT-Conector (SOA / BDO) for operators, wholesale product (BDA), specification of the product procurement and resource management, Dashboard to monitor portability process, BDO ENUM / SIP Redirect product.
- Architect and Senior Business Analyst in monitoring the specifications and the Number Portability project in partnership with Neustar.
- Senior Number Portability Process Consultant to telecom operators.
- Pre-sales Consultant and Solution Architect in charge of solution architecture and technical proposals for number portability, integration and professional services;
- Database cleanup process (names, addresses, equipment).

Promon IP e Promon Tecnologia Ltda, São Paulo, 2000-2007 Main Achievements:

- Design of Promon's Portfolio for OSS/BSS, Security and Infrastructure Products responsible to support network integration solutions;
- Preparation of Technical Proposal and Business Plan based on Products and Integration Services from Promon Portfolio that was responsible for all revenue from software integration;
- Process and architecture Reengineering based on TMFORUM reference models which improved selling based on consulting services.

Work History:

- Engineering Manager responsible for the OSS/BSS portfolio management and strategic planning involving Provisioning, Assurance and Billing solution, Value Added Service Systems, Security Solutions (Firewall, Intrusion Detection Systems, DDoS Protection Solution, Security Support Systems, IT Infrastructure involving servers, storage, environments in high availability (Cluster), virtualization and consolidation environments, and solution integration;
- Consultant for Telecom Operators in strategic review of systems architecture and definition of system's roadmap strategy;
- Senior Architect Operation Support Systems working with Procurement solutions (Workflow, Activation and Inventory), Service Assurance (Fault Management, Performance, Testing, Trouble Ticket) and Billing (Mediation);
- Product Manager in charge of preparing the strategy and business plan for the Unified Messaging System product;
- Systems Engineer in charge of technical proposals and architectural designs regarding Integrated Network Management Network, OSS and Unified Message Systems based on various technologies and vendors like HP (Openview), Cisco (CiscoWorks, AR, ACS, RPMS, CNR, CIC, ISC, MARS, CWSIMS, PGW2200, CTM, MWR, SESM, NetFlow, BAC), Sun (cluster, server, storage, LDAP), Nominum (DNS Vantio), Openet (FusionWorks), IBM (Tivoli, Netcool) CA (ehealth), InfoVista, Amdocs (Cramer), Syndesis.

Promon Eletrônica, Campinas e Promon Telecom, São Paulo, 1986-1999 Main Achievements:

- Network Management Product Development (SALCOM II, SALCOM) which was a pioneer product for Remote Monitoring and Surveillance of Telecom Equipment;
- Data Communication Product Development (TRANSDATA) which allowed Promon to increase revenue;
- Packet Data Communication Product Development (COMPAC) that allowed integration between old and new packet communication products;
- Process Control Product Development(DYNIX) that allowed infrastructure update from VAX based to UNIX based HW platform.

Work History:

- Product Engineer for specifying a new Remote Terminal Unit for SALCOM II;
- Design and Coordination of outsourcing process for maintenance of deployed systems;
- Consultant as solution architect to design am integrated management solution for Globocabo:
- Consultant as solution architect to implement a proof-of-concept of an integrated management based on HP-OEMF framework for HP-Consulting in Argentina;
- Coordination of software development team in charge of design and development a Q3 interface based on HP-OEMF framework in partnership with HP-BID(Germany);

- Coordination of software development team in charge of SALCOM-TMN project (system based on HP-OEMF framework in order to integrate the various existing network element management systems, initially integrating SALCOM II system);
- Coordination of software development team in charge of SALCOM II (2nd product release of a large remote telecom monitoring system) through three complete cycles of development (from pre-sale to post-sale);
- Systems Analyst in the implementation of levels 2 and 3 of the COMPAC system X.75 protocol and the setup of development and test environment;
- Coordination of software development team in charge of the Management Subsystem responsible to find the minimal path between nodes and to configure the logical connection of TRANSDATA system II (Networking Deterministic);
- System Analyst in implementing the software functions of historical data and standard interface with the operating system on DYNIX project (Generic Platform for Process Control System);
- Systems Analyst in software implementation of various subsystems of the project SALCOM including some software embedded solutions (RTU Remote Terminal Unit and Communication Control Unit).

High Scool - Instituto Salesiano Dom Bosco, Americana-SP, 1990-1991

Database Teacher.

Recent Courses:

- Data Analyst Nanodegree Program, UDACITY, 2017 in progress
- Software Product Management Specialization Create Better Software using Agile Practices, COURSERA (University of Alberta), 2016 in progress
- Developing Innovative Ideas for New Companies: The First Step in Entrepreneurship, COURSERA (University of Maryland), 2015
- CMMI Introduction, ASR, 2007
- Cobit 4.0, IT Partners, 16H, 2006
- IBMEC Consulting Sales, 16H, 2006
- Project management Fundamentals, FGV, 32H, 2006
- Project Feasibility Analysis, FGV, 24H, 2006
- ITIL Foundation, IT Partners, 16H, 2006
- NGN Network Management, SLA Theory and Application, NGOSS styled Model Driven SOA, TMFORUM, Nice, 2006
- IBMEC Presentation Technics, 16H, 2005
- Advanced Modeling Concepts An Integrated Approach to SID, MTMN and IPNM, Using NGOSS to Build the OSS/BSS for Lean Operator, Introduction to OSS/J – A Foundation to Implementing NGOSS Using OSS/J, TMFORUM, Nice, 2005
- A Practical Guide to Implementing the eTOM, eTOM: Practical Uses and Real Implementations, TMFORUM, Dallas, 2003
- Solution Selling, Concord, São Paulo, 2003
- HP OVC/SA Technical pre-sales, HP, 16H, Rockville-USA, 2000
- HP Powen-on for Technical pre-sales, HP, 16H, Rio de Janeiro, 2000

Recent Congress, Summits and Workshops:

- Mobile Payment & Cards, 2015
- Meetings GUGST (User Group of Third Party Services Management)2015/2014
- SmartGrid Forum 2013/2014
- ESC BRAZIL Electronic Systems & Components Brazil 2014
- Gartner Application Architecture, Development & Integration 2013/2012
- MicroChip MASTERS 2011/2012/2013
- MEF LATAM M-Commerce Summit, 2011

- 4º CMEP Electronic Payment Means Congress, 2009
- SBCARS 2007 Brazilian Symposium on Components, Architectures and Software Reuse, Campinas, 2007
- XI e X Annual Conference "The Future of Technology", Gartner, 2006 e 2005
- III Annual Conference "IT Outsourcing", Gartner, 2006
- TelemanagementWorld, TMFORUM, Nice, 2006 e 2005, Dallas, 2003
- ITU Telecom Américas, ITU, Salvador, 2005
- Unified Messages, SLA in Telecom, TMN Implementing, *Billing* and *Customer Care*, Fraud in Mobile, IIR *Conferences*, São Paulo, 1999 a 2001;